The size of black holes is insane. One
of the smallest known black holes is
J1650. Its diameter is about as long as
Manhattan, but it's got a mass of 3.8 of
our suns. Step up is this black hole,
Messier 15. It's about the size of Mars
with a mass of 4,000 suns. Now, we're
getting to the lower limit of what's
considered a super massive black hole.
This one's about the same size as our
sun, but 100,000 times its mass. And get
this, the black hole at the center of
our galaxy, Sagittarius A, is about this
size compared to our sun and has 4
million times its mass. We captured this
image of it in 2022. Now comes the truly
insane. The black hole in galaxy M87
weighs 5.4 billion suns. It was the
first to be imaged in 2019. And then one
of the largest black holes ever
discovered weighs a whopping 66 billion
times more than our sun. And finally,
there's Phoenix A star estimated to have
a mass of 100 billion suns, but we
haven't measured it directly. And Ton
618 is farther away than Phoenix A star,
so we're seeing it farther back in time.
We made a whole longer video all about
black holes.